# 今天给大家做一个什么呢
What are we making today?
# 做一个豆豉辣味鸡翅
A spicy chicken wings with Douchi
# 辣味鸡翅
Spicy chicken wings
# 蒸的
A steamed dish
# 实际上这鸡翅
Actually cooking chicken wings
# 单独用鸡翅来做菜
cooking chicken wings only
# 这个时间不会很长
It won't take too much time
# 因为什么过去我们很少有
Because in the past we don't have much resources
# 专门卖鸡翅的
A place that sells chicken wings only
# 一个鸡就俩鸡翅
There is only one pair of chicken wings froma chicken
# 把这鸡翅剞剞花刀
Make a few cuts on the meat
# 已经改好刀了
I'm done making the cuts
# 我们稍微少搁点盐
We should put just a little bit of salt
# 因为我一会还要拌料
Because I need to mix it with other ingredients too
# 所以这盐不能太多
Hence the salt cannot be too much
# 搁点酒
Put a little bit of cooking wine
# 多搁点
Put a little bit more
# 别太多了 还有呢
Don't put too much of it, we have other seasonings too
# 还有别的菜呢
We still have other ingredients
# 您搁点白酒么
Do you want some baijiu
# 别搁白酒
Don't put Baijiu
# 有的白酒 尤其那曲酒
Some Baijiu liquor, especially Qujiu (a type of Baijiu)
# 搁错了以后它臭
If you put the wrong type, the dish would have an unpleasant smell
# 这二锅头没事
Erguotou is okay
# 二锅头行 清香型的
Erguotou liquor has a delicate fragrance
# 这稍微给它腌一会儿
Marinade the chicken wings for a while
# 腌一会儿 很简单
Just a while, it would be easy
# 搁点葱姜么
Do you want to put some spring onions and ginger into it?
# 葱姜也不要
Nope
# 待会我这炒料里边有葱姜
I will stir-fry some spring onions and ginger later on
# 切点小料
Mince some spring onions,ginger and garlic
# 炒一汁儿
Let's make a sauce
# 锅里放点油
Put a little bit of oil into the wok
# 先把这个豆豉给炒炒
Stir-fry the Douchi first
# 郫县豆瓣酱
Some Doubanjiang from Pidu District,Chengdu
# 这个不能太辣
The sauce cannot be too spicy
# 弄点牛肉末麻婆豆腐出来了
Add some minced beef and this would be Mapo Tofu
# 小火慢炒烹酱油
Cook the light soy sauce with low heat
# 来点老抽也行
You can add some dark soy sauce too
# 红烧酱油颜色深没问题
With Hong Shao dishes, it's ok to have a darker-coloured sauce
# 你看红烧这颜色就起来了
Look， the colour is showing
# 少来一点点水啊
Put a little bit of water
# 您再来点水淀粉不就行了么
You can add some slurry, isn't it?
# 不要 我就要点水
Nope, I just want some water
# 要点水得熬点味
We need the water to cook and enhance the flavour
# 就不听二伯的
Just don't listen to Er Bai
# 得啦
Done
# 因为有豆瓣酱 它肯定咸
The sauce is kind of salty because of the Doubanjiang
# 咸它有点苦涩味
The saltiness might bring some bitterness
# 搁点糖它就融合了
Put some sugar and it would smooth the bitterness out
# 搁点糖
Add a little bit of sugar
# 这个呢要加点淀粉
We need to add some starch into the wings
# 你看见没有加上淀粉它就滑啦
Look, the chicken wings have became smooth and glossy
# 起嫩 起滑
The meat would be tender
# 拌点淀粉
Mix some starch into it
# 这就完活啦 看看这劲
Look at this, it's done!
# 你这一蒸就完了
You left the last step only which is to steam it
# 你弄的我们俩的菜都是复杂的
Our dishes are much more complex compared to yours
# 是啊 到你这简单啊
Yeah! Your dish is simpler
# 简单当中不简单啊
There are always some knowledge in simple things
# 这要让网友看着简单
We have to let the audiences to learn some easy dishes
# 老抽
Dark soy sauce
# 您这还得拌点香油呢吧
You have to mix some sesame oil too
# 要的
Yep
# 拿香油封面
Use some sesame oil to seal the flavour
# 再来点
A little bit more
# 别介别介一会油太大了
That's enough, or else it would be too oily
# 腌上十五分钟
Marinate it for 15 minutes
# 锅开啦
The water in the pot is boiling
# 下锅
Put it in
# 一个是豆豉单一的口感
If you have the flavour of Douchi only
# 叫豉香排骨
it can be Douchi pork ribs
# 当我搁点郫县豆瓣酱呢
What if I add some Doubanjiang?
# 豆豉辣排骨
Spicy Douchi pork ribs
# 我们用什么样的辣椒都可以
We can use whatever chillies we want
# 那我要是搁点泡辣椒呢
What if I add some pickled chillies?
# 豆豉泡椒排骨
Douchi and pickled chillies pork ribs
# 关键是把鸡翅腌好了入味
The key is to marinate the chicken wings until the flavour penetrates
# 爱吃烂糊的蒸一小时
If you prefer really tender meat, steam it for an hour
# 因为这鸡翅很快就烂了
Because the chicken wings can get overcooked and mushy easily
# 爱吃硬一点的蒸四十分钟
If you prefer the meaty texture, steam it for 40 minutes
# 就啃着吃
Just bite it and enjoy the meat
# 吃起来就方便
It would be a convenient dish
# 其实家常菜就是下饭菜
Actually home-style dishes are appetizing dishes
# 对就是下饭菜
Yeah, they're appetizing and make you wanna eat some more rice
# 这就是下饭菜啊
This is a dish that goes extremely well with rice
# 吃得香 吃得多 吃的猛
You can eat a lot of it and really enjoy the flavour
# 就是好吃
That's what we called "delicious"
# 吃的舒服
The food comforts you
# 吃的还健康呢
And it is a healthy dish too
# 开锅吧 一小时了
Let's opne the lid, it's been an hour
# 到点啦
It's time
# 你们要不提醒啊
If you guys did not remind me about this,
# 我还真的差点把这茬给忘了
I almost forgotten it
# 看见没有
Can you see that
# 你中间怎么偷偷换了一盘啊
Why did you change another plate in the middle?
# 不是 刚才那个碗小 太多
Nah, the bowl was too small and it's overflowing
# 嘿 王奶奶和玉奶奶就差这点儿
Hey! The little things make a big difference!
# 对 就差这一点儿
Yeah, the details matter
# 滑 不错
Smooth, not bad
# 三叔你吃一下
Try it, San Shu
# 吃的味道怎么样
How is the taste?
# 太好吃了
It's very yummy!
# 突出了豆豉的香气
You can smell the aroma of the Douchi
# 辣的正合适
and the level spiciness is just perfect
# 这叫什么
What is this called?
# 有辣 不过于辣
There is a hint of spiciness, but it's not overpowering the dish
# 辣而不燥
Spicy but not to over
# 0:03:44.180,0:03:45.600
# 好吃好吃
# Awesome flavour
# 一嘬就下来
The meat comes down easily with just a bit
# 很香很香
Very aromatic
# 真的很香
It's truly aromatic
# import ending.srt 00:04:03.660 稿件内请原样保留此行